-[keyboard clattering]
-[gentle music]
I hate it when we get
stuck on security duty.
Not me, because I
love to quash dissent.
Sure, I love a bit of
dissent-quashing, too.
Only problem,
there's never any dissent
in the administration.
[applicant yawns]
-Was that a sigh of dissent?
-Huh?
No, I'm just tired.
[yawns]
You sure? Not a blatant call
to rally others against a system
that treats you like
a cog in the machine,
devaluing your
individuality and identity?
No, it's fine, whatever.
[sighs]
Guess there's just nothing out
of the ordinary
going on around here.
[upbeat music]
[keyboard clattering]
[whooshing]
[metal thuds]
[vacuum whooshes]
[Arin grunts]
[Sora grunts]
Sorry.
Empty?
Weird.
[Sora] But perfect for
what we need.
Man, our first
solo ninja mission.
Just you and me,
like the old days.
What's the deal
with this place again?
Last time I was in here, the
agents said they find people
that went missing during
the Merge and return them,
but I think they were sending
people to the wrong places.
If they found
my missing parents,
they could've sent
them anywhere!
Still, if the administration
is good at anything,
it's record-keeping.
They probably kept
notes of-- Hey!
-[machine beeping]
-What's happening?
Looks like the records
were taken offline
when the head of the Department
of Realm Reassignment,
some guy named Agent Walker,
went missing.
[Arin] So info about my parents
could have been here,
but I waited too long
to get it?
[sighs] What's wrong with me?
I got distracted by ninja stuff.
If you consider saving
the world a distraction.
-[door thuds]
-[Agent Underwood] Yes, yes!
Finally some dissent!
It's quashing time!
♪ Lost in the unknown
so much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[flame roaring]
-[thud]
-[dragon roars]
[gasps, sighs]
-[Nya] Anything?
-[Lloyd] A lot,
but not what I wanted to see.
-Like where Ras' Dojo went?
-Exactly.
Master Rontu teaching me to
find harmony with my visions
has been an enormous help,
but that doesn't mean I can
make any sense of them.
I saw Wolf Masks training,
but I have no idea where.
Or who the
mysterious master was
that Ras called out to
during the blood moon?
What kind of being could
have that much power,
to make an entire Dojo
disappear like that?
No clue.
And until we figure it out,
it's like we have no idea
what our next step should--
-Whoa!
-[fire crackles]
Playing through!
Kai once told me Boulder Golf
would increase both
my power and accuracy.
-Fore!
-[fire crackling]
Wyldfyre's been
training non-stop since...
Since my brave, stupid brother
got himself trapped forever
in the Nether Space.
Wyldfyre's trying to live up to
what she thinks Kai would want.
[Lloyd sighs] I know a thing or
two about thinking that way.
But I'm worried she's putting
too much pressure on herself.
Says the king of putting
too much pressure on himself.
That's how I know it's bad.
And she's not the only Ninja
trainee I'm worried about.
I expected to hear
from Arin or Sora by now.
I'm sure they're fine.
Agents, present arms!
[Agent Underwood] You better
turn yourselves in, punks.
We have blasters
and injunction paperwork,
and we're not afraid
to use either!
Better listen to her.
My partner's vicious
with her paperwork.
She'll bury you
in 9-21Cs so hard,
you'll wish you
51A-ed your 39-ZZ!
I don't know what
any of that means,
but we should be going.
Hey, let go!
Those are my favorite feet!
[both thud]
We can't get captured
on our first solo mission.
Lloyd will never let us
out of the Monastery again!
[gas hissing]
[Agent Allen coughs]
I bet that smoke bomb
isn't even licensed.
Dispel the vapors!
They've completely vanished!
Impossible!
It must be some form of magic!
[feet thudding]
[growls]
[laughs]
Great to see you too, Riyu,
but we gotta move.
They might figure out where
we went any second now.
Seriously, where'd they go?
Oh, we'll never figure this out!
[car engine roaring]
Mission was a total fail, Riyu.
If the administration had any
clues to where my parents are,
those clues are gone now.
It's okay, Arin.
I'm sure we'll track them
down with some other lead.
What other lead?
-There is no--
-[Riyu roars]
[car tires screech]
[Matriarch thuds]
What was that?
We've got to check that out!
[car engine roaring]
[thrilling music plays]
[car tires screech]
Whoa!
It's a dragon!
[Riyu roars]
It's the Matriarch of
the Mountain Dragons.
Riyu's tribe mother.
[emotional cries]
[roars]
[gasps]
Someone took her horns!
[roars]
We have to help her!
I'll call the others on the
explorer's long-range comms.
They'll take forever to
get all the way out here.
The Matriarch needs help now.
But what can we do?
This is the Land of Madness.
Riyu has a lot of friends here.
[Riyu roars]
[fists thudding]
[grunts, groans]
[clangs]
[Ras] Cease, Nokt!
This is training, not war.
[panting]
Everything is war.
Save your anger
for when it matters.
Your skills have improved
since I freed you, Nokt.
If you're so impressed
with my Shatterspin,
why don't you take off this
blasted control implant
so I can really let loose?
Because I don't trust you.
I respect the Forbidden Five,
but I am in charge here.
And I do not need
a knife in my back.
Reset the match.
We need to be at
peak fighting form
if we're going to beat the
other elemental competitors.
[feet thudding]
The Craglings really do
treat Riyu like a hero.
They wouldn't use the healing
mud from their Sacred Field
for anyone else.
Yea, but I'm not
sure it's working.
[dragons roar]
What exactly happened?
Someone attacked the Matriarch
and stole her crown of horns.
Who could have
done such a thing?
[growls weakly]
What's this?
I'm Wyldfyre of
the Fire Dragon tribe,
and this is Heatwave,
my tribe father.
We're here to help.
[Matriarch roars]
She's in bad shape. We need
to work twice as hard here.
Come on!
[Matriarch roars]
[tree thuds]
Do you all hear that?
She's saying something.
[Matriarch roars]
[dragons roaring]
[emotional cry]
How could someone do this?
Why would someone do this?
Right before she passed,
I heard the Matriarch's
voice in my head.
-Did anyone else hear that?
-What did she say?
She said, "The Source
Dragons are in grave danger."
-[hatchling chittering]
-You hear that?
[moan]
[chittering continues]
Is that crying?
[gasps]
[sudden, happy cry]
[both growling gently]
The Matriarch's child.
This baby's gotta be the next
in line to lead the tribe.
Whoever killed the Matriarch
must not have known
this kid was
in one of her mom's
nursing pouches.
[hatchling chitters]
Don't be afraid, little dragon.
We're going to protect you.
And how exactly are we
going to protect this baby?
What if whoever killed
the Matriarch comes back?
Only one way to keep it safe.
We have to take it
back to its home tribe.
[chitters]
Great idea, but big problem.
The Mountain Dragons
moved after Rapton
and the Claws of Imperium
found them, remember?
We have no idea
where they live now.
[sighs]
[Riyu roars]
What's that, Riyu?
Is that your home, Riyu?
-[Riyu roars]
-Sure, but what about you?
Oh, I forgot!
Remember when Riyu left
his tribe to come with us?
The Matriarch told him he would
always be able to find them.
That's right!
But how does he do that?
-[dragons groaning]
-[Riyu roars]
He seems to think the tribe
is in that direction.
Are we sure he's right?
[yells]
The other dragons are sure,
and dragons have way more
common sense than people do.
Then let's go!
Thank you for your
help, Craglings!
[gentle music]
[both growling gently]
[ship whooshes]
[Riyu growls]
Riyu, we've been
flying a long time.
It's okay if you need a break!
[Riyu squawks]
We sure he knows
where he's going?
I'm thinking yes.
I've never seen him
this determined.
[guns blasting]
That's right, Ninja!!
-It's the return of--
-Rapton?
Aww, I was going to say that.
You stole Rapton's moment!
I thought you and the
Claws of the Imperium were
on our side now?
You helped us take
down the Empress!
[scoffs] I was never
on your side,
I was just on the
Empress's side even less!
And we're not the Claws
of Imperium anymore!
We're the Freebooters now.
[wicked laughter]
-Attack!
-[guns firing]
What does Freebooters
even mean?
Your boots are free?
Told you no one
would get it, Rapton!
I never liked the name.
Freebooting is what pirates do!
Lawless adventurers, like us!
Haven't you ever read a book?
Aah!
Imperium doesn't
hunt dragons anymore.
Oh, trust me, I know.
I was out of a job, and
after I spent three days
as a shoulder pad consultant...
[fire crackles]
...I realized Rapton isn't
cut out to be a wage-earner!
I am a freebooter!
The name still sounds stupid!
Your opinion is wrong!
So now, I'm a mercenary
that sells dragons
to the highest bidder!
And it pays awesome!
I can afford twice as many
unicorn figurines now!
[guns blasting]
Huh, easier than I--
How dare you kill
the Matriarch!
What are you talking about?
I haven't seen
a Tribal Matriarch since
that time you blasted us
with that weird power!
You're a liar!
Would Rapton lie?
We heard those dragons
howling and checked it out.
And you got a baby dragon!
You know how much that's worth?
-[jet thuds]
-[Lloyd screams]
Whoa-ho!
Rapton's about to strike gold!
Oh, come on!
This isn't a fair fight!
-[Rapton screams]
-[jets thudding]
You'll pay for this, Ninja!
Pay for what?
Are we selling them something?
[Rapton] It's a figure
of speech!
[gentle music]
Wow, the mountain dragons
must've made
the World Forest their new home.
[gentle bellow]
[sad moan]
[roaring in unison]
I promise you, we
will find who did this
to your Matriarch, if
it's the last thing we do.
-[hatchlings roaring]
-[gentle music]
[chittering]
Today was not what
I was expecting.
Finding info on my parents
was a complete fail,
and now we have the death
of the Matriarch to solve.
Where do we even start?
[powerful whoosh]
Who are you?
I go by many names,
but you would know of me as
the Source Dragon of Motion.
No offense, but I've
met a Source Dragon,
and let's just say,
you're a little short.
I suppose it is not fair to
expect you to recognize me
in this mortal form,
but this is the ideal way
for me to interact
with you ninja.
Look, I was told firsthand
that Source Dragons don't get
involved in mortal affairs.
-So how do we trust--
-Enough!
[fire crackling]
Yeah, I'm thinking that's
a real Source Dragon.
I come here in
need of your aid.
I fear the Source Dragons
face an unseen menace.
As the Matriarch died,
I heard her in my mind.
She said, "There was grave
danger to the Source Dragons."
The Matriarch of Mountain
Dragons is not the only dragon
of her stature to have
her life taken in recent times.
What, there've been others?
The Matriarch of Fallen Leaves
and the Patriarch
of the Northern Spiral,
their crowns also stolen.
These dragons all fell
under the powers of myself
and the Life Source Dragon.
I fear whoever is
doing this is coming
for the Source Dragons next.
[fire crackles]
But you're a Source Dragon.
You're more powerful
than anything!
I wish that were always true.
But as you know, one of our
kind was recently captured
and contained by mortals
with evil intent.
And before that, the
unthinkable happened.
A Source Dragon's very
life was extinguished.
We didn't know that.
In this post-Merge world,
even the Source
Dragons are not safe.
What would happen if there
aren't any more Source Dragons?
We have existed since
before time had a name.
We are the source
of all elemental power
in this universe.
We hold together
the very fabric of reality.
Okay, yeah,
so no Source Dragons
would be very bad, got it.
Why are you telling
us all of this?
It is not our custom
to involve ourselves
directly with mortals,
but these are dire times.
Of all the mortals, you have
the strongest connection to us.
We trust you.
I need you to find who
this hidden threat is
and stop them before more
Source Dragons are destroyed.
You have so much power,
can't you just, I don't know,
look down and see
who's doing this?
That is not how
our powers work.
The other Source Dragons
are blind to the dangers.
I come here on my own.
I need your aid.
-Where do we even start looking?
-That, I do not know.
Wait, I found this
in the Matriarch's claw.
It looks like part of a map.
But there's not enough of it
to tell where it could be.
[Nya] Those streets don't
look familiar at all,
and I studied a lot of maps
when I was in Cloud Kingdom.
It is the City of Temples.
City of Temples?
Home of the Tournament
of the Sources.
What, like that Tournament
of Elements thing
Master Chen tricked
everyone into?
Not a competition
founded by mortals.
These are cosmic games,
the legend of which may
have inspired imitations.
So whoever
attacked the Matriarch
is somehow connected
to this Tournament?
Perhaps.
It is the only clue we have.
-Your path forward is clear.
-Clear?
You will enter the
Tournament of the Sources
to discover the identity
of our mysterious enemy
and stop them before
it is too late.
[upbeat music playing]